# **CORMAC MCGLOIN**

PRODUCT DESIGNER

## **Skills**

User-centred design

User research

User interface design

Wireframes

Interaction design

Information architecture

User journeys

Coded prototypes

## Tools

Figma

Sketch

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

Framer

Principle

Zeplin

## **Programming**

HTML 5

CSS 3

SASS/SCSS

Javascript

React

GSAP

Git

## **Education**

## **Bachelor of Arts, Photography**

University of East London

2008 - 2011

## National Diploma, Graphic Design

Wigan and Leigh College

2004 - 2006

## About me

I'm a design consultant who helps businesses understand their customers and improve their products. Combining an eye for design with a methodical approach to research and frontend development skills means that I have taken projects from the planning stages right through to implementation and beyond. I have experience working within the agile methodology and scrum framework.

# **Experience**

## Senior product design consultant (contract)

Moneyfarm | August 2020 - January 2021

Helped to deliver optimised website and app experiences by improving the consistency and efficiency of the design system. The work I did allowed the design team to communicate more effectively with other teams.

#### Senior design consultant (contract)

Zoopla (via 101 Ways) | June 2019 - March 2020

Instrumental in the planning, designing and implementation of a centralised design system at Zoopla. This led to increased consistency for the end users, greater efficiency for the designers and engineers and an improved onboarding experience for new team members.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Arroe | November 2018 - Present

Designing the website and app for their smart battery. Packaging design for the product and collateral for the business.

#### Senior UI designer (contract)

River Island | July 2018 - March 2019

Improving the user experience throughout the River Island site. Research methodologies included, competitor analysis, white paper research, data analysis, in-person interviews, usability testing and multivariate testing.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Havas Life Medicom | June 2018

Producing user interface designs for a pharmaceutical website.

## **Email designer & developer (contract)**

Harrods | April - May 2018

Designing and developing various email campaigns for Harrods and their brand partners.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Beauty Pie | January - March 2018

Reviewing UI patterns to help create a unified design language and make the user journey more intuitive. Hosting daily calls with developers to aid with code implementation.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Spafax | November - December 2017

Producing user interface designs and style guides for the websites of various airlines.

### Lead designer & lead front-end developer (contract)

Catapult Sports | July - October 2017

Lead designer and front-end developer for the new PlayerTek website.

## Senior UI & iOS designer (contract)

Arroe | May - June 2017

Designing a concept app and single-page website for a new tech product.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Topshop | February - June 2017

Helped to unify the desktop and mobile user experiences by creating consistent UI patterns across all device sizes and producing a style guide that would be the single source of truth.

## Senior UX/UI designer (contract)

Hudson Shoes | July 2016 - February 2017

Redesigned key pages of the website including the homepage, PLP, PDP and checkout journey. Designed and coded key landing pages and email campaigns.

## Digital & print designer (contract)

Lufthansa | September - December 2016

Producing digital and print designs for Lufthansa and its subsidiaries.

## Senior UI designer (contract)

Practicology | May - July 2016

Designing key pages for the Hobbycraft and Dreams websites.